what is boppin my bro tato chips
it is i the host of the junkyard love
podcast
gumby today we've got my friend tim
fraley on the podcast we actually start
this episode out right after this intro
it's gonna go right into him playing
singing a song uh
performing a song that he wrote an
original song from him i tried to kind
of sharpen it up and make it sound
okay um but i didn't do too much so you
know i
i just kind of on the fly gave the poor
guy like said hey
wait what if you sing a song right
before we start so he didn't have any
warm-ups he didn't have any
time to plan or prepare or whatever so
that's kind of like a musician's worst
nightmare but he did great
it was awesome that'll be the intro as
far as the
the dog goes in the background we've got
a couple times they're barking and
trying to cut it out when i could
towards the end they're there yipping in
the background but it kind of turns into
background noise after a few
so uh i am grateful that you guys are
still rolling with the punches just kind
of experiencing the
the newness of trying to switch over to
zoom and the occasional remote podcast
since i don't have the same studio
anymore to have the same space so
just kind of rolling with the punches
rolling with the changes um
trying to edit the audio how i can
trying to meet up with people where i
can
and continue bringing you the episodes
and just trying to have um
have these conversations so i'm glad you
guys are listening if you enjoy
give it a thumbs up give it a like get a
follow share whatever
interact with it i appreciate it take
care of yourselves and enjoy this
episode with tim fraley we'll see you
next episode
[Music]
well the first time i met her i was
already behind she had a one foot out
the door
had her hand in mine
[Music]
her mama told me son can you
handle the gypsy so i said that girl
right there now she's got a heart of
gold
[Music]
they won't know
as fast she came into my life
a door slam a k-10 a taillight
gypsy so where'd you go
i'm still here
ain't nothing out there to see
what you couldn't see with me
[Music]
gypsy so why'd you go
leaving the love here
[Music]
will your friends try to tell you yeah
they
do the best they can
ain't easy changing the heart of a man
i do my best to pick up the pieces i was
never there to start i look in the
mirror
give a gypsy my heart
[Music]
gypsy show where'd you go
i'm still here nothing out there to see
you couldn't see with me
[Music]
gypsy so why'd you go
here
[Music]
it's been countless bottles countless
nights since i've seen those taillights
she called the other day she had
something to say
she said she's coming home oh my did you
wrong i said
gypsy tipsy
gypsy soul no no no
fools cowboy wants you'll never fool him
twice i know it's
only a matter of time till the wind
takes you back
into the night i said gypsy
gypsy oh gypsy
soul
[Music]
gypsy song where'd you go
i'm still king girl
[Music]
ain't nothing out there to see now
what's up
you couldn't see with me
[Music]
gypsy soul i gotta go no point in
staying in here
[Music]
well we'll see how he does dude that's a
hell of a way to start a podcast
that was so enjoyable actually a little
nerve-wracking but yeah i mean i told
you
just for the record for anybody
listening i totally sabotaged him there
i'm like
didn't even give him any heads up on it
he had no warm-up no
vocal warm-ups or anything i'm like you
should play songs i'm doing
sober january so no no whiskey courage
on that one
yeah isn't it crazy how much that helps
to not just be like overly
neurotic and i mean just like uh yeah
just a couple uh a couple sips
and you're just it takes the edge off i
mean yeah it's even like the environment
for me it's even just
like i can be three drinks into a beer
in just that comfort of having that
thing in my hand
yeah and sipping on it it's like a
little little friend in your hand yeah
geez uh when uh tim ladies and gentlemen
tim fraley hello hello i appreciate you
coming on the podcast buddy this is
thanks for having just
by the way jake came all the way out to
the oc heights here yeah oregon city
it's a bit of a drive no i don't mind i
don't mind long drives
i just i mean i end up listening to a
bunch of podcasts in my car anyway so
yeah
it's no big deal gotta just take blue
down here he gets to hang out with the
doggos to some extent so yeah
um hey how long you been playing guitar
like when did you start playing guitar
um i started playing
gosh my brother bought a uh
like esteban guitar like on the tv show
like the
info info like tv thing like total
gimmick guitar
and then he never played it and i just
picked it up and i started
playing it um that was probably
i don't know probably freshman sophomore
year
yeah yeah yeah dang it how old are you
know
33 33 yeah oh dude it's sounding good
though i'm glad you're still doing it
when did you
when did you first write your first song
like were you singing though
was that a big gap or was that right it
was actually a pretty big gap yeah
because um cause that's a whole nother
beast like learning how to
pull lyrics from from the muse while
also like keeping in time and playing
with your hands
that's just a huge jump yeah it's um
gosh
it's probably probably
probably three or four years till i
actually started like i mean i would
write songs but you know you're just
like
not really it's just more like some
stuff yeah some stuff oh it's paper and
a couple chords but like practice which
is basically what i'm doing now but
it's just a little more put together
yeah you can say that about anything
really yeah
what really helped me was actually my my
brother-in-law um
is actually a musician singer-songwriter
um shout out to dave brinker he's on all
the
channels he's got he's kind of like a
country definitely country vibe
but it's a uh the songs are more
tailored towards people from like the
west and like
you know this area right which is
different i mean if you actually listen
to like country music
it's like i mean there's stereotypes but
usually i mean we all know there's like
going to be some red dirt somewhere
um you know about 35s you got some
gravel roads
you know there's a beer yeah that's
something about your sound system in
your truck you know it's always like
but his stuff's very much it's like a
songwriter like kind of like
takes it back to like the 70s where a
lot of the music was like actually like
about stuff yeah it wasn't just like the
same song cut up by somebody else
yeah he's saying the same thing with a
different clap track yeah yeah basically
i mean i don't know i enjoy because i i
like pop music i mean i'm a dj i feel
like i have to like pop music in a sense
but i generally do enjoy it
and i like pop country too yeah but
i do recognize and i know very well like
the difference in between the two like
they're completely different moods when
i want to listen to one or the other
yeah i mean when you're when the
singer-songwriter is is
telling you a story like they're
basically communicating a mood
or a feeling or an emotion to you
through
like a three and a half minute chunk of
your time rather than just like
putting the right things together to
make your to make you you know enjoy the
beat or tap your foot or whatever
yeah yeah i like to like think of it
like story time versus like at a party
you don't really need to pay attention
at a party necessarily it's just like
something that keeps you
keep the bpm's up 100 you like it or
it's just like a fireside might be more
like oh let's hear what this guy's got
to say
yeah yeah no that's true because i feel
like with songwriting uh songwriter
type of music rather than just your you
know pop music or having a beat on the
background it really is kind of a
you're more prone and you're allowed to
kind of just stop to kind of pause
yeah you know whereas like imagine if
you're at a a pumping party and
someone puts on a song like everybody
don't say a word for the next four
minutes yeah you're gonna listen to this
people would be
they wouldn't want to do that but um
yeah that's super good man i
i i mean i've heard you
i think a couple times i know we
definitely you i
heard a good amount when we were in
shasta last year yeah but again that was
man i thought it was great i don't know
if it was i felt like
yeah that's the thing you were out
drinking on the boat all day yeah
it's like the last thing we're doing
before we go to you know try to find a
bed
is like oh play guitar like oh yeah yeah
drinking all day and then like
mark and i somehow talked to you you're
just along for the ride we talked him
into like oh you
should play tonight yeah definitely play
yeah
then the uh what's your name close the
whole bar down which wasn't really
a thing but yeah but it's not a very
open bar
yeah but yeah uh it was fun gosh i
forget her name debbie debbie
debbie from jamaica so debbie from
jamaica she um
lives in jamaica and she comes here like
every memorial day and labor day
or i think even longer than that um
but she she does like a bunch of cool
stuff she like donates like school
supplies and
she brings back a bunch of stuff with
her and brings back food with her and
stuff and
um i think she has businesses and
restaurants and stuff down there but
that's the bar owner of the
uh the the place where we were basically
forcing tim to go up on stage and play
for us
yeah it was fun i think mark or you
turned the stage lights on
yeah yeah at some point yeah we found
them that place is cool man
it's super yeah super dope yeah it had
the vibe where it would have been
totally comfortable for you to play like
where i don't think people would be
if that was a pack play something was
coveted so it wasn't very packed but but
i think people would be pretty tentative
like maybe
casual conversations low-level
conversations but
they wouldn't be just like full-on
partying talking over you as you're in
the background i think that would have
been
some sort of mutual respect um do you
play any other instruments
um so actually i started playing piano
um
and then my teacher moved to japan
so i just stopped playing damn do you
feel like you made like
strides in it and piano yeah no no
what what what was your teacher teaching
because i'm i'm taking lessons right now
um once a week but i feel like it's i'm
going like straight from like the very
first page of the book that you got
families on like
very because it's weird my knowledge
about music and my like natural
because like i have rhythm and i i have
like skills in music
but they're learned through djing yeah
and so it's weird it's there's a lot of
stuff that i kind of know or my body
understands but i don't know the
terminology i don't know how to recreate
it
honestly honestly i'm still there right
i mean i i guess
i mean my mom always likes to talk about
it she would get in these conversations
with the teacher on the phone
and the teacher's like tim doesn't know
his music
and she's like yeah he does he plays it
all the songs you guys were
like practicing yeah she's like no he
just memorizes it
he's not learning anything but
so like not learning like i mean it is
but like in place but the problem is
like i guess i have
like really i guess good pitch
so i can figure out notes and stuff like
that so it made it way easier for me
i wouldn't read the music i would just
hear the hear it
and play it yeah and so she was like
he needs to know like the basics which
is true like and even now like
i mean with guitar like if you
if i read a music with a note in like a
letter form
i could play that but if you throw out
like the actual like written like
hieroglyphic of what a note looks like
i'll be like
uh what is that someone read this for me
it's a g oh
i can play that yeah no that's how i've
been i've been when i learning piano is
like
i'm like starting super bass bass level
where i'm learning how to read music
which is
it's interesting because it's
it seems separate than music itself like
i'm you have to because you have to
start at such like a small like all
right this
this is the c and here's how you make a
c on here and here you see when it's a
whole note here's a half note here's a
quarter note and all that stuff
but um it's it's like partly frustrating
because sometimes it's on the surface
it's hard to
communicate like what am i the thing i'm
learning today how does that correlate
to me being able to
play music later on like actually be
able to write songs and move my fingers
around but
slowly but surely i am seeing myself you
know i'm able to
to be looking at the book and not look
at my fingers and still kind of like
follow along yeah
little by little but so how are you
doing on piano like you're
i well i don't have a piano so you might
have to get one
i do i want a keyboard dude they're not
that expensive
yeah yeah i like to get i like to get
back into it because i enjoy just like
messing around on piano still yeah
whether i know what i'm doing or not
but well i think even being being able
to just like sit down
and for fun try to figure out like some
cover songs or to just write something
yeah i mean you got to know um your your
basic
you know like wonder wall wonder wall
yeah some third eye blinds
you know throw that in there hey but man
if i've been having some drinks
and we're at we're at a campfire and you
pull out your guitar and you play
any of those songs i'm with you i'm i
know i'm so pumped to hear it honestly
it's cliche but everyone likes to hear
them i'm happy being basic
i'm very happy being basic i remember
the last camping trip you went on
our uh our mutual friend emily she sent
me a couple videos of you playing guitar
oh yeah yeah
it was like oh man i wish i was there
yeah
that was that's fun yeah so that so you
played gypsy soul for us which i have
heard before and i really like that song
i told you that last time
um do you have anything like online that
people can listen to
yeah uh no no no do you have plans to do
anything anything like that i do
i do yeah like um kind of circle back to
my brother-in-law he's
released uh two albums
and some some singles um
and uh blue
we're trying to have a conversation here
blue this guy he has no respect
hey we're talking
come on bud the other dogs are taunting
come on
it's okay bud
all right i think we're maybe good for
now
an occasional bark that's just kind of
what you get like i feel like cove had
opened the door for that
because everybody had to go it's not
everything so professional and like high
quality the standards are kind of lower
people are just like was he working i
think yeah that was a good podcast
yeah there was a barcode sounded like my
house yeah exactly
real people talking real things so
anyway you're talking about your brother
yeah brother-in-law um so he he's
um he was a marketing uh guy
for um a hunting gear company called
sitka
and so he he would always go to all the
you know shot shows and all the hunting
expos and stuff like that so he met a
lot of
like people that i guess you know the
country music and hunting kind of go
hand-in-hand right
um but he met a lot of people that were
i guess you know kind of like
gatekeepers in a sense um they just had
connections and stuff like that and he
made friends with a lot of people and
he's always been a singer-songwriter so
um he just kind of cultivated a lot of
those relationships
and uh he
ended up striking up uh um
a really close friendship with the swann
brothers
which i think uh zach swann
maybe both of them they were on i think
like second place or something in the
voice or something a few years
two years ago yeah and uh never heard of
them but they're in nashville
um and he went down there and basically
uh they had a whole band and everything
uh set up and he said it was the
craziest thing ever he's like i just sat
down
played all my songs acoustically and
they just stared at me with their pens
and paper
and he's like it was weird he's like and
then i started playing and all they all
just start writing
he's like it was just he's like i was
like almost interview or something
caught off guard yeah he's like but
they're writing notes they're writing
music
and then oh wait so wait so they're
they're they're potential
singer-songwriters themselves like no
there's
so he he's basically this is like the
process is like he's
he wants to record his song so he has
the band just listen to him
and they're all just listening to him
play his songs they catch the key
you know the chords you know the music
and they write it down for like a
bassist or
uh a fiddle or you know the drummer wow
and so he's like
he's like he played a couple songs like
okay okay all right they go into the
studio and they just play a song like
right off the bat
and he's like i wanted to cry he's like
i never heard
like my music turn into like a full-on
like band he's like it was insane
because that's the beauty of musicians
like the fact that you can you can hear
something
and especially talented musicians like
you know okay here
here's where my instrument would come in
with this guy's acoustic guitar yeah
that's crazy
yeah so for me so there's the in there
obviously um
there's the money aspect of it it's not
cheap but it can be done actually
especially now in days
where full albums really aren't the
thing anymore it's like
you release one song with like a theme
on like
you know whatever spotify and then you
release another song there's singles
kind of
singles yeah you know um so i'll
probably i definitely want to write more
and get like a solid like i mean i have
a lot a lot of songs that are
finished or not finished but i'd like to
get like solid like eight ten songs
and figure out like maybe five or six to
actually go for down there
do you think you have enough to fill up
like okay these are solid these could be
like an ep or something
yeah like i know i have like three solid
ones yeah
um but i'm just working on trying to
figure out either new new material or
going back to some old material maybe
see if it's still
still worthy right right um yeah because
i i tend to get a lot of like
writer's 80d and i'll be like this is a
good this is a good verse or this is a
good lyric and start writing it you're
like yeah it kind of sucks
well dude and sometimes you can get to
that level you uh
you're like oh this is fire and you're
like in the right mindset and you write
a majority of the song
and then you go back later like okay
i'll finish here i'll add the last verse
or i'll tweak the chorus whatever
and you're just like in a different mood
almost and you can't reach that
emotion that you were at when you were
riding it yeah it's definitely you want
to catch the flow the wave when it's
when it's when the iron is hot first
yeah it's just
i mean especially for me music's like a
release
um just for you know feelings everything
which is which is great um but it kind
of makes it hard
when i rely on it for that instead of
just being creative
that makes sense where i feel like some
of my best stuff has been like like oh
screw that chick
she sucks i'll write a great song about
her though dude and then burst is like
like i'm feeling good today let's just
write a song i'm like oh
i don't have anything anything to jot
down that's how it is it's i have a
sticky note that i keep on my on my
keyboard that says don't strangle it
yeah and that's how it is sometimes it's
like
you're trying hard and you're like
trying to get this lyric whatever and
you're like oh yeah
i'm just i'm suffocating the dang thing
yeah because it needs to be a natural
thing and a lot of times
a lot of times you just gotta you gotta
just catch it yeah it's just
it's just like throwing a net whatever
the muse is
we just like musicians and artists they
just like throw a net once in a while
like oh [__] i got one like let's try to
get it onto the recording so i can
remember it and
and write it down well it was like when
you first got here um
we were talking about a song i just
wrote that i thought was good
and then i like was playing it recording
it and playing it back to myself
and then i was like oh man i thought i
had a full song here and it's just a
half a song
yeah because i just started rearranging
it i was like no it's not right
took that verse out that course is out
and then i'm like
okay this sounds better we're getting
there but now then again i still got a
half a song
yep so well and then now you got to see
if you're even able to
to catch that same vibe you know to like
sit down and get yourself in that same
mindset to write the rest of it
right and it's you know like i'll talk
about him again but
my brother-in-law has been great to like
lean on as far as like uh
mentor as far as you know writing and
and advice
because you know he's he's older and
he's done it forever
but you know his his tips are just like
you got to ride every day
and it's something i don't do and i need
to do and i've been it's one of my
things i want to do more this year it's
like
what's one of my goals is or is one of
my goals is to write
more i don't know if i could get every
day but i'll try to get it every other
day or so
right yeah every other day just be like
all right how many times have i written
this week oh
three times cool i'm good i feel good
about that four times cool
yeah whatever i mean it's just it's just
like kind of anything else with with
habit or
um you know you go to the gym forever
and it's normal and you get good at
lifting weights or being you know
exercising and staying in shape and then
you stop for like
six months or a year and you go back and
you run a mile and do
a set of biceps and you're like this
sucks yeah like
i suck at this now you know and that's
kind of how it is like i'll i'll
pick up the pen and paper and i'll be
like oh yeah yeah yeah this is good
and then you come back to it and you're
like i can't finish this
100 you know it really is like you have
like it's like a muscle
you know yeah yeah you got to keep
working it out yeah i've i've noticed
like my uh my
at that at the old house the studio
there like
had such a vibe i curated it i had spent
so much time down there it was like
it was a really comfortable spot where
it was like i could pretty much turn
on when i walked in walk in there it's
like if i need to write music
again i haven't like written anything
that's worth listening to
i don't know you have a song oh yeah oh
yeah that's a good song
that one was pretty good i guess that
one was okay but but i haven't finished
it
and i haven't finalized the um like the
instrumental
like i mean these are all excuses that
all musicians just say i guess
but uh but i have noticed you know since
since moving out of there like
i didn't i was almost taking it for
granted like how much of a portal it was
for me as a creator like walking into
that basement into my old studio
was just like i could write anything
that i want to at least get a start but
um
since then it's been i mean september
october so it's been a few months
and um i have trouble like
writing writing lyrics now i've been
able to write
i've been able to write raps like
because i
i enjoy writing raps i think it's i i
think like freestyle rap i've i was
going i've been going off about it
lately but
it's it's one of the most fascinating
things to me i'm not good at it myself
but it would be very cool to explore
more um
so i've been writing raps but man i am
i'm like one tenth of the way there from
where i was able to get to when i was at
the old place so
i think it's the same thing like but
that was my schedule was i would wake up
and i would just pretty much have
freedom to go downstairs and like listen
to music and i could start writing music
within first couple hours of waking up
and just
chill stretch listen to music write some
music listen to me to cry some music so
you definitely have to
keep those things sharp or like be
around it yeah it's tough like i said
you gotta you gotta really you know
stay on that that mental you know
um almost like
i don't know it's like a schedule you
know you know it sounds
kind of weird because you're creating
something but you almost have to be on a
bit of a schedule
yeah because that's just like like okay
sometime today i guess gotta get it done
just do a little bit
yeah yeah maybe not like okay 2 p.m
sharp
yeah exactly like like isn't that the
thing where you it's
another don't strangle it situation
where you as a as a musician you've got
because you got to work
like you gotta show up and do your job
if it's your job yeah and if you're
especially if you had a point where
you're like this is my full-time income
is making music that's
that's where it changes but it's it's so
it's hard because when it comes to
creativity or like even like a
a painter or someone who's creating
content or you know musicians of any
type
it's it's hard enough to take yourself
serious
and it's hard enough to um
i don't know i guess designate the time
and really follow through with it like
so
if you're not at a place where you're
making money off music sometimes when
you
you spend six hours a day on a song like
playing acoustic guitar as much as you
enjoyed it
sometimes it's almost like a little
course of anxiety
where you're like dude i just spent six
hours playing my guitar yeah so it's
i don't know sometimes there's a balance
of just enjoying it
trying to actually make something to
create something in the end
and then also just just striking the
balance with wanting to be a creator
yeah yeah so true yeah
they're up and down now we've got we've
got uh
we've got tim's dogs over on the other
side of the door and we've got blue in
here because
they were they were getting a little
wrestly so we're trying to keep them
chill yeah they're very dirty out there
blue is nice and clean fresh haircut
inside he did get a fresh air cut his
first haircut
i mean technically he did get like the
smallest the tiniest trim
months and months ago but he got his
first haircut and it's a proud dad
moment i'm having
the first haircut
um what was the last live show that you
went to before
kovic shut down uh that was
uh red shahan at
bunk bar bunk bar that sounds dope yeah
this is a sweet super sweet little bar
uh kind of like by
uh off water avenue in portland by omsi
okay okay which is super weird because
very portland um red is a
very he's uh he's a texas underground
texas
country artist but it's countries
loose it's it's more like
bluesy country rock right um
it and it has like a 70s vibe which is
kind of cool okay i'm into it
yeah so it's it's it's almost like
hipster country
if there's such yeah exactly right so
you would think you
you know he you know you're like country
importantly like whatever
yeah yeah but it was it was cool seeing
all the different types of people there
was
really awesome like you got people that
show up in you know the romeos and then
people that are like
got a leather jacket on and like pointy
boots and you're
just obviously very hipster but it's
like everyone's just vibing
that's the thing about music is it
brings different types of people
together yeah i mean i've
i love music festivals blue paws off
the counter young man no man or this guy
um i i'm a big fan of music festivals
and like
just being able to go i love
being able to see that exactly like the
different types of people where
you almost don't like you'd probably
really never have a reason to talk to
the person next to you yeah but when
you're vibing to the same music you're
in the same zone you're singing it
you could take a glance to your left and
right make eye contact with them and
it'd be a smile all around
yeah you'd never even know that was the
total vibe there was just like yeah this
is awesome
it was weird because like he's so
unknown in general like out here
like i remember uh i mean i followed him
on like instagram before
i actually you know saw him but i saw
him pop up on one of my
apps i had for like shows in town and i
was like no way it's like 15 bucks what
and uh i remember going to the bar and i
was ordering a beer
and he was at the other end of the bar
which is kind of long it was a long bar
i talked to the bar keeper and i was
like hey can you get can you ask
red if he wants a beer and he's like
who's red i was like the guy who's
playing tonight
and then he's like oh and he like goes
over and asked him and then he read like
looks over and he's like gives me the
you know the hang loose and i was like
yeah and i got him a beer we ended up
i'm catching him at the at the end and i
talked to him for a little bit but
super cool guy but yeah it was kind of
funny even the bar pretender didn't even
know who the guy was
yeah super lucky yeah oh that's cool
that's a good that seems like a good
last show before that it really i mean
it really didn't plan on it but yeah but
yeah it ended up being kind of like a
really cool
yeah yeah i was planning on seeing uh a
couple other people but
you know obviously kobe did mm-hmm so
yeah take our damn feet out right from
underneath us
i can't wait i was talking with a
podcast yes yesterday we were talking
about basically the
when it does come back whatever that
looks like
like whatever live events look like or
if they're small first or it's just like
little bars were able to do their thing
um he was saying he's like it's
definitely like the roaring 20s for sure
people are just gonna go in but i mean
and then at the same way though i mean
imagine
i imagine working musicians have been
just busting ass and like challenging
themselves and really probably
questioning like what do i want to write
about you know what do i want to
so i imagine the new albums that we'll
see that people
like wrote while while quarantine was
going on like once we actually start
finally start to hear those albums and
those lyrics that's gonna be some good
[__] i feel like
yeah yeah yeah i think well uh is it
more uh more morgan uh
is it walnut or wallet yeah
he just he just like screw it and he
just dropped like 30
tracks on his new album oh did he yeah
he's just like
we're just gonna do it what hell yeah
yeah get him out yeah i mean i feel like
people you know before kovit it was
definitely a lot of artists probably had
so many in the bank at all times like if
you're if you get if you get on and you
have like a record label or you're like
you're you know top of the spotify
charts what what you would probably be
doing is just cranking out
tunes yeah and they're not gonna get
released it's not like okay i finally
finished it i sent the masters over i
get to release it tomorrow
there are songs that don't see the light
of day for like three four years
you wrote tons long ago they're still
going through the approvals of samples
clearing
and then like make sure the the
guitarist who recorded got paid the
outfit is good
yeah yeah so it'll it'll be cool you
know once we do
it's impossible to like know what it's
gonna look like when we
come back into live events and just
being able to hear anybody but
i'll say dude even just sitting here
across the table listening to play
guitar is so enjoyable
like i miss i miss live events like
i mean it would be enjoyable even if
there was live events still right
but it's just nice to hear someone
express something and like
you know just be human people performing
music is
so pure you know yeah i love it
it's it's so great yeah yeah like i said
it's good it's definitely good uh
i mean for most for most artists but
even for me it's
uh
you know again it's songs i can read a
song that i wrote and be like oh
i was going through this or that
happened or you know or what was that
doing you know
yeah it's almost like a little a little
tear back into like
your past where something was going but
like it doesn't like i don't even think
about necessarily
why i wrote that song for some of these
newer songs that i like to write like i
like to sing still
um like that song like i i'm not still
hung up on this chick
but but at the time like you know it was
just kind of like a
i wanted to process it and then i was
just like this is how
like the best way i could figure it out
to process and like
just kind of put it out there in music
and then yeah move on
you know did you have a thing where you
write it and then you like listen back
to it at some point and you're like oh
uh the question i'm trying to ask is do
you ever
step back after you wrote it and you
didn't even realize kind of exactly what
you were going through or exactly how
you felt
until you listen or like you see
yourself you know you write the lyric
and then you read it back and you're
like
oh damn yeah that's actually exactly
that that's a good question because
there's actually a lyric in this
gypsy soul song that i wrote and then it
wasn't until i kind of like
sing it a few times i was like dang that
was good yeah
that's so true it was it was um
basically like um
uh where i'm obviously i'm the guy in
the song
but or whoever but it's me but basically
looking into the mirror
is basically looking at yourself and
knowing that you knew what this chick
was she's not she's a runner she's not
going to stay around you
you knew the whole time you have no one
to blame
for giving you her heart or you know for
you giving you know her
your heart so it's like you know
but after like after i wrote i was like
dang that was good that's a good line
that was a good life i did i love that
it could be so profound with lyrics i
was listening to um uh
mike stud who's a rapper he has a
podcast and he had
uh huey mack who was another rapper on
and they were talking and huey was
saying his
writing style he'll like listen on loop
to a beat
and he'll write one lyric at a time and
then he'll like go into the booth or sit
in front of the mic
and record that one or that one like
rhyme like eight bars or 16 bars
at a time instead of just like writing
the whole thing seeing what it goes
so he was saying a lot of times he'll
just go line for line
and then he'll okay i got enough or i
finished the song
and then he'll listen back to the whole
thing and he'll be like oh damn
i didn't realize i was going through
that i didn't realize that's what i
wanted to say
yeah so it's so it's another view of
don't strangle it is you know kind of
get out of your own way
you know get out of your way let the
muse or let the creation or the emotions
that you're trying
your self is trying to process and like
let that happen on paper
you step back yeah that's that's a good
way to do it
i think another thing that i found
myself in some of the songs that i've
written
is like they're as far as writing you
need to know
there's like a line where the song is
too personal
it's like you can't really like that's
that's for you and yourself
right if you play it in front of
somebody it might be people will be like
whoa
tell me how you really feel bud or be
like wow that's
that's pretty crazy dude you all right
yeah you know still
like like this song that you know gypsy
souls like it's a you know it's like a
kind of a breakup uh
getting over a girl song yeah but
writing in a way that
you know it gets out obviously a pretty
blanket
thing going on with the story but it's
not but it's not like
but it's not like you know her name was
so and so
and and i hate her and you know it's
just like really personal very yeah
yeah it's like oh that's exactly who
that is you want to make it
you want to make write a song where
people can relate you know or it's it's
vague
enough that and it also it you know a
lot of
a lot of it's true but there's also some
stuff that have added in that
it's more like i don't know more of a
situation that more people have been in
right like like she
she went to a different state because
that was her plan the whole time
i just sum it up to gypsy soul because
everyone i feel like
people know who would know a gypsy soul
or dated their gypsy soul or maybe they
were a gypsy soul
so kind of like oh yeah i totally get
that it can kind of
you know it's yeah you want you want
people to relate to
you know basically your music or what
you're trying to convey yeah because if
it
versus it's just like i'm saying it's
just like that's so personalized it's
like
yeah i mean well and so i'll enjoy like
in
in hip-hop a lot of times i'll enjoy the
storytelling um
like very personal like a train with no
love by andre nicotina
is one of my favorite songs andre is
great yeah yeah that's cool you know
uh and it's like he's literally telling
this story about how
he was with one of his best friends
that's a great yeah he was like selling
rocks and he got popped and he went to
jail
yeah yeah so like that's a very personal
but like that that's a different
listening experience
though like that's a that's like a
songwriter like rap
yeah like you're like whoa like that's
heavy yeah i was always really drawn to
that
that style of rap growing up i mean even
um
like like guys today you know even like
nf for example like i i
like a lot of i feel like he does paint
a pretty good picture of
a scene that's like a lot of it's
relatable but a lot of it is just
specific to his life yeah
his emotions and stuff obviously he's
got some stuff he's gone through or
going through
yeah oh i love his music yeah he's
really good i saw him uh i saw him with
with logic um and he put on a show but
it was really interesting to see like
it it's it's interesting to see someone
like nf be famous
because he is like a very introverted
i have my black hoodie on and like try
not to talk to me sort of guy like
i mean i don't i don't know a ton of his
background he might be like more
friendly and
more talkative than i know but um just
witnessing like the openness of logic
who's big
logic is huge he's got fans of all ages
he comes out and he's just so positive
he's just you know his chest is open
he's just loud he's big with his
movements and then comparing him to nf
who was on before
who's like wearing a hoodie like he's
killing it but he's almost like more
closed off he's almost like experiencing
like if you were if you were watching
you know the joker perform a monologue
that he wrote himself
he wouldn't really be addressing the
audience or like performing for the
audience he's almost kind of like
pacing in his room talking to himself i
feel like that's kind of the vibe that
nf
gave off on stage is he's kind of like a
like he's going through his own mental
thing
and he's almost talking to himself while
he's rapping and we're witnessing it
yeah where his logic is talking to the
crowd yeah it's yeah it's almost like um
an f is like he can see like maybe like
a ghost of himself or an
alternate of himself and he's like just
talking to himself that's a lot how i
feel like his
his songs versus yeah like someone who's
just projecting it like
yo wow party get crazy yeah that's kind
of a weird vibe like taking like the
crowd way down you know
it's like like really intimate like oh
wow some deep lyrics then you have like
next coming out just yeah
what's up yeah you know they honestly
were a good duo though like
the contrast between them wasn't super
weird i i
remember i remember i enjoyed it as as a
participant myself but i remember
watching because i was just like
observing how the crowd's reacting like
the people around me
there's a lot of like young kids around
me you know 14 16 year old teenagers
yeah they knew every lyric to nf songs
but they also like they were rapping
every lyric they were feeling the
emotions you know i'm like maybe they
were shedding a tear i don't know but
then logic comes on
and they know you know they know a lot
of his lyrics too but they were also
that's when they
moved their hips and they're having fun
so the contrast was actually pretty good
that's cool
yeah that's cool i was at moda center
though who knows what that'll be back up
yeah um yeah man that
i think the last show that i went to was
a grandson
if you ever had or ever heard of him um
he is a
man how do i describe it he's kind of
like modern
rock i guess okay um
it seems like like it almost blends in
with with some sort of rap i guess too
um so far he sounds terrible but uh
but but his he's kind of like uh uh like
[__] authority okay uh he has like
raging us a machine kind of
like that thrash thrash muddle kind of
yeah actually kind of like that that's
that's a good good example but he has
kind of like some um like modern
elements like there's like kind of a
an edm vibe to some of the schools yeah
and he's he was a really great performer
he put on he's like
um i remember i went to warped tour when
i was younger
and uh rise against for example yeah
like they were very i remember thinking
they were so cool because they're like
[__] the government and i was like you
know i'm 14.
yeah i [__] you covered you know i'm
all along with them i thought it was so
cool
yeah i just thought it was so crazy i'm
like what like they're allowed to say
that yeah they can do that so
it's kind of the vibe i got from
grandson um and i went with my friend
tyler so
it was a good last show i obviously
missed live shows but uh that was a good
one you'll have to check out
grant's grandson i'll i'll put them on
my little search i'll send you some i'll
send you something somebody sent me some
a little
little nibbles of cookies there a little
nibble cookies
um hey so you're doing you're currently
doing a break from booze
you want to talk about that yeah i guess
yeah what
are you doing 30 days uh yeah i was
actually gonna do uh
two months two months yeah yeah i think
i'll just do a month
you're gonna do a month yeah that's
that's so good it smells impressive i've
never done it before so
yeah i i've been drinking since i was 14
and it's like
like i would have times where i look i'm
sorry can you say that
what can you say you've been drinking
since you're 14. oh well now i'm gonna
go to jail i think if it's over 10 years
ago you're good yeah you're good right
yeah if i got in trouble for something i
said in my podcast i'd be so annoyed
that i roll so hard
but uh but i mean i've been
because i've done like sober october and
stuff yeah it's crazy to think
dude it was like it was freaking hard it
wasn't easy and it's not that i drink
every day but it was just
on the weekends i drink or like my
social things that i do when i go like
bs with homies and stuff you
you have a beer in your hand you know
right and the same like i i
i'm not uh i wouldn't qualify myself as
like an alcoholic
yeah but you know like again i would
drink you know one or two days on the
weekend friday night saturday night
um maybe a little bit into sunday get up
that hangover gone or whatever
um but you know during the week i'm not
really drinking
yeah um it's it's been rough because you
know i
you can't you can't see here on the
podcast but uh i uh
i've become quite the bourbon and
whiskey connoisseur you definitely have
a lot of
so it's all just good stuff yeah it's
all just sitting there we'll have to do
one of these
we'll have to do one of these i'll come
over and try a few of those we should
when you're not on there
you got to stay though because oh of
course
you do like six tasters and you're
toasted oh dude i would probably do
three tasters i get i i don't drink as
much anymore so
yeah and i feel like a lot of my um
my body is is pretty healthy nowadays
like just a lot of my like supplements
and my diet and my
yoga and fasting and stuff yeah i do
notice the effects of alcohol a lot
quicker like i can i bet
yeah three ipas is enough to i'm like
whoa oh boy
you see and i even gave up on ips a
while ago yeah like i
i mean it's definitely i feel like a
northwest thing
yeah but sure but uh i mean i love them
you know and then you get like the
winter ales and stuff and it's just like
it just they started like screwing me up
you know yeah just like
each bottle is like a you know it's a
meal basically
just so heavy it adds up quick too yeah
so i got to stick to those lattes
coors lattes the
yeah so you've been how do you feel what
what's today we're
22nd 23rd oh so you're you're like
pretty you're on the
downhill slide are you doing all january
yeah well like it was like a
i started a little late like the first
it was like on the fourth i think i
started or something weird
uh but yeah so i'll go into february a
little bit but
uh yeah i remember our mutual friend
mark uh
we were texting about it and uh he's not
doing sober
but he's like just doing it on the
weekends but uh he was like yeah you
know it's
you know we should probably just we're
like in agreement we should just
try something yeah and he said the
comment was funny he's like yeah just
you know to
make sure we can and there's and there's
not a problem
and i was like oh well you put it that
way dude i mean
that's the thing it's it's it's funny
because it's this conversation where
you're
where you know we because we
we have just weird words like alcoholic
you know yeah like and
and you know because there is people
with legitimate like problems and
foreign alcoholic is someone who's just
like blacked out drunk on the side of
the road every night you know
and it's it's it's not even about like
labeling it or about
i think you just have to look at
different people's lives have just been
a certain way like me i've when i was
when i was younger before i ever drank
my parents drink every weekend like we
had parties all the time where there's
just a much adult drinking and
it's not necessarily a bad or a good
thing it's just kind of how
my life went yeah it's just part part of
your life yeah yeah and it's
uh i mean dude and we honestly a lot of
the stuff that we do like
stuff that like me you and mark have
done like stuff that it's
very enjoyable without drinking but it
is really enjoyable to throw a beer into
the mix
yeah through shots and mix you know and
just get a little more liquid it's a
rock o'clock
soraka clock yeah we definitely turn up
when we go to shasta man yeah that's uh
yeah i prep for that one dude i gotta
like i i i gotta rush
i would do one i got a rough rundown of
it before like you know
with with mark and he's like you know
it's gonna get pretty crazy and i was
like all right all right
and then you know like we go to the
liquor barn or liquor expo whatever the
place was and then
rolling out just way too much alcohol
yeah
but i mean it's good deals you go down
just over the border for any listeners
who
are going to washington you go just over
the border in california
and i think it is called the liquor expo
yeah i think it is it's a gas station as
well
so hey they have gas so you can get
gassed up in both ways yeah
and uh dude they just yeah we always buy
a ton of booze there yeah i used to
anyway so
yeah so um but honestly yeah i'm feeling
pretty good yeah
um i'm still waiting on the whole like
exercise thing i need to need to
incorporate that into this somehow do
you do any sort of exercising now or uh
well
i'm up on my feet all day at work
mechanic but
it's not you know it's not the same i
mean that is better than it's better
than
like sitting on a chair in front of a
computer for sure but yeah i've been
sitting in front of a computer quite a
bit
but i need a i need to incorporate you
know some type of uh
i just feel like in general i'm not
really stressing myself
and like just like i i kind of miss i
miss
hurting in that sense like i used to
work out a lot
you know as i was in good shape but that
was now i'm looking back like oh that
was like three years ago
you know four years ago now it's like ah
i think that's how life turns out to be
like you just you're off and on with
certain things well
and also you know i incorporated a
girlfriend into my life back then who
wasn't into
being like working out and stuff and i
was always busy and i'd feel bad
like if i come home late and like i'm
gonna go to the gym and then like yeah
come home
from the gym then go to bed right you
know you got you got to try to balance
it out i
never could figure it out so i just
wouldn't it wouldn't go so what you need
to do to him is you need to go
your next girlfriend needs to you need
to get her from the gym you need to
just you don't have to get a membership
just chill in the parking lot this won't
be creepy don't worry
it's true because if you hit him hit on
him in the parking lot it's different
than hitting on him in the gym
yeah yeah and then and then you could be
like hey listen you're cute i'm cute i'm
just i'm just looking for workout
partner that's all and she's like do you
go to the gym like no i'm just looking
out for
someone who i thought was healthy and
beautiful this will work
and uh yeah those are nice yoga pants
bless yoga pants really yeah really yeah
yeah it's the best
thing ever i love mine
i got some man yogi so i got some man
yogis i love those things or they do
just like the underneath uh like yeah
they're i think they're
uh they're actually like uh
that uh columbia they have like that
reflective
reflective like silver stuff in the
inside they're like a thermal
oh but i wear them like when i go skiing
yeah yeah i just wear those and then my
ski pants and i'm warm
yeah perfect but just you know i've also
just worn them around the house i feel
like kind of weirdo but
like these are comfy yeah i i'll wear
long johns around the house too it's
like
you take off your pants that you were
wearing that day and you just have this
long johnson
great i'm already inspired i like the
little tight cuffs around the ankles you
know you have to
yes i like that i think it's good i i
put my socks on
first and then those yeah so then it
like really locks in
there you go there you know yeah i do uh
i do i do yoga pants i have like some
it's like nike and adidas um and i wear
those to
i wear those to yoga but i'm still
slightly insecure like i wear
shorts over them because it's like you
can see the outline of my bulge and
stuff yeah
and i'm still insecure but it's annoying
because i'm actually like hey
i'm let's not sexualize everything like
i've got it's just like
you know a woman has you know she's
walking around with her curves i've got
my curves
yeah it's it's been a hard it's a hard
it's hard for me to leave the house
though with the confidence of
like oh my shirt's long enough but once
i'm doing yoga poses like
i don't know let's do it it feels like
i'm wearing i remember i did that one
time uh
me my buddy we we got done skiing we
went to
it's closed now but it was like a burger
joint coming down from mount hood
it's just a bunch of burgers i can't
remember that place but
i just had my yogurt pants on like my
sweatshirt
and my boots then walked in to to the
the burger place and i think they
thought we were probably together
and they but just like the the looks i
was getting people just like
strange yeah do you want champagne and
orange juice
like no i want a beer oh okay all right
not an idea yeah i mean i don't know i
feel like in a couple years
stuff stuff changes so quickly with like
what's acceptable
especially with clothing you know like
clothing has over the last
five years like anybody can wear like
any pretty exuberant colors or outfits
yeah without being questioned that much
like most people don't turn their heads
as much
or if they do i guess i just don't hear
it yeah but uh i i bet i bet in a couple
years it'll be pretty normal for dudes
to wear yoga pants
bulge and all right i mean we have got
to even playing field here you know yeah
the girls got the whole
you know the whole the whole
their body showing yeah you know why not
maybe maybe we'll roll out there and you
know
start our own little moose knuckle
nation you know moose knuckle nation
okay dude dude i think i need to title
this have you
have you seen there's actually a
clothing brand in like canada called
moose knuckle
and it's like of course it's from canada
yeah but it's like it's like this like
luxury like
you know gucci brand and i'm just like
man
you can't they cornered the market i
mean yeah
i mean it's even like making your brand
a talking point like if you're
like it's true i mean they have to know
yeah we it can't just be like an
american thing hey what what what brand
yoga pants are those oh these are camel
toes
yeah these are the camel toes like what
no
it'll be more acceptable we'll be
wearing we'll be wearing our spandex
like if you're going to name it moose
knuckle your clothing brand
that shirt 200 bucks yeah what
you own a moose knuckle yeah yeah yeah
and then people are like well oh they're
shirts they're luxury oh okay we buy
them yeah
i don't know i wonder how i wonder how
fashion's gonna change
with with i mean it's already changes
quite a bit from social media and stuff
but
i'd be willing to bet that people are
buying significantly less amounts of
clothes just because like like you don't
go out you don't go
true you know just everybody's on zoom
meetings like
you know you're wearing the same old
shirts people are more and more
comfortable with
you know a lot of girls wear don't wear
makeup much anymore
they don't wear um like they're not
gonna dress up at home which i think
it's cool i think it's all
maybe we'll be like less consumer
because of this like we'll stop buying
as much clothes
yeah i mean maybe maybe buy less clothes
but yeah more booze more booze i think
booze has gone up a lot alcohol sales
have gone up quite a bit a lot
i think just in general like yeah most
of the illegal drug sales have gone up
and alcohol weed that kind of stuff yeah
i mean
i mean now that it's now that it's legal
wait
is i think because we're in oregon
what what was the do you know the deal
with mushrooms being legalized here
yeah is it like fully legal so
i feel dumb every time i try to
understand it i think from
don't don't quote me on this but i think
it's just for
i don't know if it's going to be like
for sale
i think it's approved for like like
treatment
like like a doctor but but that was like
a weird like
you know um a little like snippet i read
yeah but
i don't know if it's like
over-the-counter
yeah so you can't like open up your own
mushroom store and just have people come
in yeah i didn't think that's where
we're at i mean i
because i remember when i was younger
brass knuckles there was this weird my
understanding of the law
at least at that time was you can
you can sell them at like you could sell
them at the store
but you're not allowed to own like if a
cop like i walked out of the store
and a cop's like hey let me search your
pockets he could like get me in trouble
for
having them in my pocket those those
butterfly knives too
yeah probably same thing yeah like if
you they're illegal to have or something
but
you can buy them illegal they have but
not illegal to sell what is that i don't
know
that's a weird little loophole i know uh
you know it's so funny the things that
i'm like almost about to say i'm about
to jokingly say something to drug
dealers but i'm like well
it says a podcast probably shouldn't it
yeah yeah well okay so overall
you you're feeling pretty good about
being able to deposit the booze
yeah like i said it's been rough i mean
uh
you uh people's birthdays and stuff
there's been a few
this this january and people are
drinking and having a good time and
you just kind of got my fizzy water or
yeah i've been starting to drink tea
yeah
are uh it um a roasted dandelion
roasted dandelion which tasted like
liquid nuts
yeah peanuts like yeah it tasted like
nuts
yeah which isn't that bad you know no
it's not bad yeah it was pretty good
yeah it's funny how
cause i when i've been on alcohol breaks
i'll go to parties too
and um for one you don't have as much
stamina like you you don't you can't be
there as long
it's like 10 30 you're like yeah all
right bounce yeah i mean because like
you know you love the people that you're
seeing it's great
to talk to them you know but after a
while when they get progressively more
drunk and you're sober
it's just harder to to continue the
conversation sometimes or be on their
level
right but uh i would notice that i would
i would still want that thing in my hand
you know that cold brew
so i would go get like a kombucha or um
uh one time i was like super searching
for jones soda
oh yeah yeah remember john soda yeah
it's at uh um
what is it pizza pizza they have that
yeah they have like it's usually they
have a bunch of them in their little
like
by their cash register there's like a
little refrigerator full of them
yeah i don't really even [__] with soda
i don't i don't really drink soda but
that is something that if i saw it i'd
be like
get yeah and the the labeling is always
like uh
like the the illustrations and the
labeling and yeah it's always like
people just send them and pick black and
white pictures and yeah it's so cool
put it on the bottle yeah i remember
i've talked to people about this before
but they were one of the first companies
to do that like the
labels used to be pretty like they're
exact like we're we're red we're this
color and we have our logo whatever
they were they weren't all busy but now
if you go you know you go to the grocery
store now and everything's so
busy all the cans all the bags of chips
or they have all this crazy like
they hire artists to do that stuff but
it's like joan soto was one of the first
to
to do something different like that yeah
i think so
yeah really set them apart yeah
all the crazy colors you know just a
clear bottle with like
nuclear green you know or like this
crazy like
pink color you know it's kind of cool i
i felt
i felt cooler drinking them yeah i felt
cooler i was like this is
like this is what punk rock kids do yeah
this is what punk rock dudes they they
drink jones soda you see my bottle an
artist drew on it
as you're chewing on some laffy taffy
[Laughter]
yeah it's a taking taking a break from
booze though is
i think it's it's good man every time
that i've done it
it's helped me because a lot of the
stuff we do is habit you know anyway
like a lot you know
you don't really think it very
thoroughly it's just kind of like you'd
grab a beer you throw beer in with
dinner or whatever
and um when you break i feel like what
what happens is you kind of get rid of
the sugars in your stomach and the
things that in your stomach that are
like
grown to make you um i created crave it
crave it yeah yeah
like the reason for your cravings a lot
of the times you kind of get rid of some
of those sugars
and it almost resets you like it was is
for me it's it's enjoyable like that
first beer back is really enjoyable yeah
in it but it's not like a you have one
beer back and all of a sudden you're
like craving a bunch of
a bunch of beers yeah so i think it's
just like i said you don't you don't
want to
have a problem yeah right
hey i mean i the amount of i work in a
uh package sorting facility and the
amount of because
wine for example has to be signed for
like you can't just leave it on the
porch you know
and there's that's a lot of our phone
calls are like trying to time up
there's a lot more people who are
ordering a lot more cases of wine than
ever
before that's crazy i've bought in a
couple bottles
um of alcohol yeah from like different
states and it'll show up on my doorstep
and i think you're supposed to sign for
it and it doesn't you don't have to
i haven't it's just here you're supposed
to i think you're supposed to yeah but
maybe the people are just like yeah
whatever
drop this package the training i read
says you're supposed to sign ford yeah i
know
i was just like oh sweet okay cause i
missed i missed like the
you know being here to pick it up it was
just there anyways when i got home from
work i was like oh nice
that's nice good thing my neighbors
didn't come together yeah what was your
uh what was your first tip alcohol do
you remember
uh first sip of alcohol is probably some
uh it's probably a bridgeport or a henry
weinhardt's
are those wealth beers yeah oh yeah okay
yeah my uncle
um he worked for bridgeport he was a
brewmaster there
and uh so he always had him uncles would
always have you know
craft brews underground back in the day
when it was like
you know yeah that was back in the day
that was like definitely yeah
but they were i remember just like the
smell of their breath and stuff and
you're like whoa
what are you drinking yeah god gave me a
beer did you like it when you first had
it like
did you uh not really yeah but i was
just like yeah
it's not water you know yeah yeah i mean
i feel like when you're
because you know your first type of
alcohol you're around adults and you
obviously i mean i remember i want to
look cool yeah you know so it's like i
would
i would make sure i'm not making a face
or anything like that but i think my uh
i i was i was somewhere around 14 and it
was
i think it was black velvet whiskey was
my first girl
yeah it was rough man like no no coke
no i think we just had it out of the
bottle yeah exactly
yeah i think it was like me and my
sister and a bunch of a bunch of homies
but like we would do the weirdest stuff
like we wouldn't stay at a house we
would
because we were skateboarders and so we
would like go to a park and drink it
under
yeah literally go to parks we're walking
around we're skateboarding around
at night like just walking from place to
place like
handing each other the bottle that's
like a part of me that i i'm
looking back on i thought was like
really fun it's like when you
when you're underage drinking like you
just get whatever you can get
yeah and it's just like then you're like
hanging out you call your buddies up and
you're like
hey i have like three shots of
151 it looks really old but we should
probably get turned tonight
i'll be right over yeah like dude coming
over my mom's shopping me off
at six don't tell your mom am i speaking
[__]
mom get off the line i'm trying to get
drunk with my friends
yeah it's interesting i i don't know
it's interesting to kind of think about
alcohol in our culture
you know it's just it's such a normal
thing for so many people it's
yeah it's it brings us a lot of
like if i didn't if i didn't drink
myself
or if drinking wasn't nearly spot like
thinking about my job djing
wouldn't really exist like i'm you're
playing to people who obviously want to
go
you know have fun and go out but like
like everybody is there to drink kind of
it's like
the the dj and the dance like you maybe
you go out to dance but
drinking is hand in hand with it it's
it's accompanied with it yeah it's
good it's paired perfect pairing yeah
yeah
i think it's good to take a break though
once in a while if you can no
yeah i think if you think you need it i
mean if you don't think you need it
you're doing well i [__] live your
life but
yeah if you think you need it and why
not yeah i think it's a good
good like a reflective part to just kind
of be like okay
you know maybe ease back into it and be
like well i don't need to drink that
much
yeah even though i wasn't i felt like i
wasn't drinking that much but yeah
like maybe maybe maybe i won't drink on
friday night after work you know maybe
just be like saturday or something you
know right or
it won't be like in excess yeah you know
like all right i'll had
three you know three glasses of whiskey
you know maybe i'll just
go to bed yeah you know because the part
for me is like
that that i almost get like anxiety
being hungover
because it's like you waking up you're
waking up late like i'm i just wasted my
day i'm such an idiot
i'm so i'm lazy i can't believe i did
this yeah there's stuff i need to do
yeah you have to basically give your
whole day to the hangover yeah in a
sense
and let's be honest they don't get any
easier as you get older
they don't dude i felt like it was a
full week after shasta
like it was just a haze it was just like
this weird haze i couldn't break through
it until like the next week and i was
like oh this is what normal feels like
it i feel like shasta for us that trip
is uh
oh my god it's so fun in every single
way like
we put our bodies through it anyway just
like wake surfing and just like
just being so active the whole time and
stuff and just being out in the sun
that's tiring enough yeah
but like it's it's the olympics man like
we're we're drinking we're having a good
time yeah
yeah it's a
i don't know it's uh i i'm always
my relationship with alcohol has
definitely changed i
because my my like for you anxiety mine
is i do get anxiety for hangovers but
mine's like depression
mine's like the self-loathing could not
get any more intense
and i'm just it's hard to it's hard for
me to get out of bed yeah like
normally if i can get myself out of bed
i can do some stretches i can do some
breath work you know
get some food in me some water whatever
like most of the time i can
i can get through it but i don't know
sometimes those hangovers are like
it's not just my body feels bad it's
like i hate myself so much
[__] up yeah yeah i mean but that's
you know the
inflammation is a lot of like what
alcohol does and in the morning you'll
notice you're like
your face is swollen sometimes the
fingers are swollen or sometimes you'll
even be dried out but also
swollen yeah the [__] that works yeah i
don't know but yeah
i definitely have felt that yeah well
it's it's good though i mean it's good
to like bring it to the forefront
and it's funny how it's a strange
conversation right yeah
like just talking about drinking just
feels so
i don't know it feels so uncomfortable
because it's almost like this thing we
all participate in
but it's kind of weird that you can
you can't buy as much alcohol as you
want but you can't buy it you can't buy
as much wheat as you want
yeah no there's caps on it why like you
can like well think about even i mean
i'm just i'm i'm i'm not a huge weed guy
but yeah it just seems
like a little unfair well i mean even
the the laws that we have on you can
kill yourself on alcohol but i don't
you can't kill yourself on weed yeah no
you can just smoke yourself dumb or even
psychedelics like yeah you should you
can't explore your consciousness
because it like it's illegal to use
psychedelics
but like you could literally buy a
lethal amount of alcohol
at any time i mean before 2 a.m pretty
much anywhere
yeah and at that you could walk to the
gas station all right well tonight's the
night that i drink
three bottles of whiskey and die
yeah yeah it's it's it's weird but i
mean it's been it's been a huge part of
our culture like i don't know
a ton about the the history of like
alcohol being shipped over or like what
was the first
booze to come into america um
or like i wonder where because alcohol
and wine and stuff has been
in human civilization for forever
ever yeah like beer is like one of the
oldest things
yeah ever like the egyptians drank it
yeah like normally
it's pretty crazy yeah i wonder i bet
you a lot of the stuff that we read
about old times
um like where they would drink wine or
they're drinking you know beer
or or whatever they would use in those
in their languages back then
like for you know mood altering
substances or alcohol or whatever
i bet you a lot of it probably did have
like you know ayahuasca or
or yeah they probably had a lot a lot of
intense drugs that they'd like on the
weekends they're like we're going on a
[__]
journey to another realm when i was
gonna get drunk we're gonna go on a
walkabout
we're going on a spiritual quest tonight
come back in a week
yeah we're gonna skip football this
sunday we're just gonna go
to the mountains of the gods yeah leave
my clothes here yeah yeah
um hey so what uh let's see what's
today's the 23rd 22nd or 23rd
the uh the beginning of the month was
the we stormed the [__] capital
yeah america did yeah dude what do you
okay what do you think
like i'm a dummy like i'm not
i don't know that much what's going on
i'm not really politically let's just
say you're better off
probably yeah for real i think most
people are but just
in the like we you know we see a certain
amount of it on social media like what
do you think
what's your opinion like what the [__]
is going on in america like if you had
to
like if someone who who lived out of out
of our country and they don't really
watch social media
and they're like but they've just kind
of heard that it's just madness what
would you say to them like what's the
elevator pitch for what the hell is
going on in america right now uh
i would just say it's probably uh tbd
to be determined that's true
it's the wild west we don't know what
stage we're in though yeah i don't know
man it's
crazy uh yeah everything leading up to
the election
then the election happening and it i
don't know
you know there's so many different
things going on
do you think it's going to chill out now
it seems like it already kind of is
it does feel kind of like it's kind of
been kind of weird yeah um
like i know just after biden got in like
they're already talking about like
opening things back up now that he's in
yeah and like
cnn i'm not like saying like cove is not
real or anything but like
cnn took away like the tracker of all
the deaths and stuff
and we did yeah it's like that's kind of
weird like i'm not saying like it's
conspiracy but it's like
obviously you know the
trump or that that party is like what
they were
you know they're very seem like they're
kind of anti everything
as far as like the covet and everything
and then
media most of the liberal media is like
pushing it like it's a massive
thing and it's you know they're
controlling that side of it and then
once their guy gets in
let's be honest he's their guy yeah it
just kind of goes away a little bit
i mean it's still here but like it seems
like there's a bit of a lull right now
i don't even [__] know like i don't
even know what my feelings on any of it
are it's like like
i mean i don't think it's fake for sure
obviously like i know people who have
had it i know people have died from it
yeah
for sure but i don't know people who
have died but i know people have died
yeah um but there is actually i mean
there's got to be some point where
like what if we had just just for the
flu like in the bottom right corner of
like
all of our news networks it's like
showing you a ticker of how many people
are dying well if you if you look into
that stat you
you would go crazy because it's if
the numbers are pretty similar to the to
the flu yeah see
but it we we're not shutting out in the
country and stuff like that for the flu
um i mean it's a new virus no one knows
or no one knew at the time how bad it
could be so i get i get some of that for
sure
like you got to be careful but yeah we
had to have some sort of initial
reaction like i think like
the first i mean the our our reaction of
doing things the way we've been doing
things
in my opinion has gone on too long like
there should have been
after after a few months maybe five six
seven months i don't know when the right
time would be they
should have a way of determining it but
there should have been like a
some sort of like where we get smart
people together to have like a real
conversation not just
like you said this you're on this team
you're on that like instead of arguing
having
actually intelligent like emotionally
mature people
it doesn't help when like the cdc or the
you know whoever says one thing
and then they roll out all this stuff
and they're like ah just kidding
it's actually this we think yeah and i
get again it's like it's it's evolving
as it's coming but it's like the same
time like
like some of these things that they've
done have been so drastic and so
i guess detrimental to you know society
or you know you know communities
it's like that's that's kind of crazy to
go to 10
when everything is kind of pointing
towards maybe a five yeah
like well that's what i'm saying i feel
like we should have reassessed at the
beginning
what what we you know we probably should
have gone to a 10 at the beginning
like like at the beginning i think we
probably should have had
the way it was presented and then like
the
like the being lied to because they
wanted they lie to the public because
they want to make sure that like the
nurses and
get all the masks on themselves but it's
like i think they should have came out
some smart person some person who knows
what's going on some person who's
honest like [__] hired dwayne the
rock johnson to walk out on a podium and
basically say
listen guys yeah here's what we do for
sure know there's a virus and it's it
and we don't know the death rate we
don't know how bad it is we don't know
where it's from we
basically say we don't know for sure a
lot of these things but
right now we've got to you know assume
the worst we're going to lock down so we
can
at the beginning to and the curve thing
seemed to kind of make sense it's like
yeah cool yeah like i i mean i was
dating a nurse at the time like
i don't want her to be overwhelmed and
having to work 22-hour shifts every day
of the week
out in some tent out in the parking lot
of her hospital right you know
but we should like we lost our [__]
mind somewhere in between because we
should have been able to reassess and be
like
okay we you know flatten the curve or we
we know now
more than we did but now we can make new
decisions but now there's just like
you know it gets all politicized and
yeah and then
the problem is you know you have states
that seem to have it under control
that don't have the same restrictions as
some of these
very you know highly restricted areas
like say like la or you know even
portland or seattle
um new york that kind of stuff um
and you know obviously the populations
are different you know
but they there they were there were some
guidelines they falled um you know and
then it seems like
they float in their own curves you know
i don't know it just seems like
some states had it figured out some
states thought they did but they really
didn't
yeah and then they're doing worse off
now yeah than the states that just
figured it out
and i don't know it's so complicated but
i know i mean i've [__]
obviously we're not the ones to solve
this yeah but well actually i have a
geopolitical degree and no oh yeah i
also went to the
gdp um blockbuster school of
uh harvard degree phd um but uh
but it's interesting to talk about i
mean you know everyone wishes they could
you know
fix it yeah right but i
yeah i dude you just hope that you know
people that
are in the know or have the power do
what's right but
when it's pretty obvious i think
everyone agrees that
there are some major missteps whether
you want to admit it or not yep
um you know especially for
you know we're looking at like whole
sectors of our country that are just
decimated you know the service industry
um music industry yeah um
yeah that's kind of it's just kind of
literally over strippers
yeah yeah i mean that's a service
industry it is it really is yeah
i mean it's it's well they did here we
had uh drive
the drive through strip club are you
serious yeah drive through strip club
what like you pull up and it's your turn
and the stripper gets so it was it was
actually really expensive
but we did it because we there's nothing
to do how was it
it was great oh i took uh you know i
took a roommate and his girlfriend and
uh their dog cash who's here um he's a
puppy so you know
girls love puppies especially strippers
uh but we
we rolled up and it was like 50 bucks
for the truck and we're like oh wow okay
all right and
you have to order food because the whole
deal is like you roll through this tent
and it's like uh the you know magic
wonderland
strippers and then by the time you get
to the end of the tent you get your food
oh yeah it's kind of cool actually it
was actually pretty cool like everyone
was super nice
and uh we rolled up through the tent and
they had like
you know smoke going and there's like a
stripper on each side
of the truck and they're going crazy
yeah and uh
they have like these big buckets you
just kind of throw cash out
or they would they take it with like the
old grandma like gripper things
out of your truck dude i love the
stripper ingenuity it was great
like it was great yeah yeah i mean
they're people with jobs that's what
they do for work like that's like the
this sex worker field is an entire
[__] field of work it's real
like we can't just act like it's not
there because we're a post-christian
society
yeah you know yeah and uh the food was
actually pretty good yeah i'll say it
right now
yeah i that's the first time i've ate as
like an actual strip
club i guess even though it's textured
you think they have you step up their
game
i think so cause that mac and cheese was
bomb like it was like cream based like
it was it wasn't just like velveeta it
was good
okay okay not just from a bag in the
back no yeah it was legit there was a
whole
it was a whole setup are they still
doing that right now i think i don't
know i think they got shut down
after that oh damn yeah it's pretty sad
but
uh yeah it was kind of one of those
things where like it was kind of like
in the midst of everything shutting down
and there's nothing to do and we're like
oh
we could go do this like stripper thing
so we drove down there and did it and
there's a line of cars people were on
the same vibe
we're gonna get some food dude i see
some boobies tonight humans
are our ingenuity man yeah like make it
a drive-through
strip club situation like [__] yeah cash
their their puppy he got to be out on
the uh one of the gals grabbed him out
of the truck and she's dancing
on stage with him it's great
[Laughter]
wow what an incredible thing i mean
it'll be interesting to look back at
i don't know i always i always try to
think of like
the you know the world after this like
when we get back to normal but it'll be
even even whatever we [__] fall into
next
it's gonna be the most interesting like
in 10 years when we look back or we talk
about this time
it's going to be like just it's going to
be the craziest thing to describe
yeah i i mean i think that's an
understatement
yeah yeah i think we're just we're just
we're still i mean
i think last week was a year no i don't
think we're out of year yet or we're not
close like the first case or whatever
yeah well because
so it was it was middle of march when
washington shut down i know that because
i was literally at a show up in seattle
with like 2 000 students yeah and
it was basically like uh like things got
serious so quick that
we're like we don't think we should be
having 2 000 people here we did we ended
up going through with the show but
i mean it was yeah but that was middle
march but before that
i remember being very stressed out
because i would reread it every night
before bed like an idiot
because i was watching it happen in
china right then italy
yeah it started to spread and i i've
played this game called plague
incorporated
if you ever heard this but it's it's
actually super sick this was before co
if this was out like a couple years ago
i had this app on my phone
and basically what you do is you create
your own like fungus or plague or virus
or um like you kind of choose what what
style
of um like like a biological
deterrent or i don't know exactly the
word but you know a virus or a fungus or
whatever
and you spread it to the world but you
get to choose basically
he gives you a world map and so like
like if you want to win
because and then you're like it's this
thing where if you don't put the proper
amount of like
strength and um like i
uh dna binds and stuff into it then
you know and you release it in a country
with high wages and with like smart
people there
then they'll get a cure for it quick and
so you want to put it like i would start
in places like india because it's a
highly populated area but they're not
it's incredibly like economically rich
and so it would spread faster they
wouldn't be able to contain it as easily
and then on the app you would have your
little airplanes flying over to other
countries and it would take your plague
with them
wow so this was a game this is insane
it's crazy how
morbid it sounds it's like they were
it's like they were someone let's just
let's just hype what they
say it was it was engineered and it's
like someone's like dude we have all the
data we need
from this game from this game but
seriously though like i mean
you had to use strategy you had to and
you would do like upgrades towards
certain things like you would choose
that's
at a crucial point in time whether
you whether this virus now is a uh
can be transmitted by mosquitoes now it
can be transmitted by mice
and so you'd see place you know like
places with subways and stuff where
there's mice
you start to see them get more infected
but if you chose mosquitoes you'd see
like
places heavily populated with like
wooded areas those get infected
so i mean it's but it's crazy that
that game did not seem as morbid and
[__] up
before the pandemic like yeah that's
just another cool game
until you you knew you were just giving
data too
crazy damn i wonder i should look at
like the app developers and see if they
are from wuhan china
they're literally from luhan china oh
man
wait does that mean that i that i
contributed to
a covet outbreak i don't know great what
a crazy game
yeah i mean but it it really it is
interesting to think you know our
culture is
our society it's just so diverse like
we're so
far detached from like you know just
being
the things that came after monkeys yeah
just being a biological organism that
like can be taken out by
a virus that that you don't see it's not
like it's so
tiny nano size i know it's
it's insane um
i think it's weird because this whole
shutdown and not having anything to do
or less to do
um i think the way
society is going to go is i mean
we know it's going to get definitely
weirder and different
but yeah just being more used to um
you know ordering stuff online not going
out to get stuff
um you know like there's a i mean
there's already like
um you know obviously autonomous stuff
is gonna be way more in the next
even just five years it's gonna be crazy
um um
drone stuff's already been cleared for
new uh
like delivery stuff yep um well that's
gonna be crazy
yeah kids are gonna be popping those out
of the air with pellet guns
i don't know if they thought about that
when i was young i would have definitely
why wouldn't you
but now they're gonna have to have extra
cameras on them like then they take your
son to jail
yeah try trying to catch the little
shits who are shooting the the drones
and pelicans but dude
when i was younger yeah like you have
like pirated amazon drones like yeah
this is
pieced together with ups and amazon yeah
it's like you have to scrub off the
fedex symbol or something yeah spray
paint it
dude that's actually probably gonna be a
thing yeah i've like okay when i was
younger i used to i had airsoft guns
like i loved those damn things yeah i
would
i didn't have a pellet gun if i had a
problem i'd probably shoot it at it at a
drone but i would have definitely shot
the airsoft
for sure i imagine kids are going to be
oh yeah but it is
it is really i think you know the whole
pandemic the whole lockdown has really
set that whole situation like all of our
autonomous
autonomous um like future growth
options have been skyrocketed and like
really locked in and
we probably we probably now are going to
have it
years and years sooner than we would
have if we didn't have the lockdown
i think so for sure yeah because they're
going to do deliveries they're going to
start
deliveries at like hospitals and stuff
like if you you know
need a heart transplant somebody has a
heart they're in a different state or
far away a different hospital they can
like get the drone to the helipad
of a new you know just like we do with
helicopters now i assume
but we'll be doing that with with drones
like that
that changes the medical game quite a
bit oh yeah just yeah and then
where's a there's a college campus that
was already trying out these little like
robots look like just like almost like
coolers
and they would like just they have
packages in them and they just kind of
roll around
and deliver packages i think i saw a
little video that yeah which college
town not very smart a lot of dumb kids
yeah like oh i stole this again it's
like
i want to see that's like the human
elements we're still so stupid
and there's like these very very smart
people that want to like really changed
like society
and everything like no this is good this
is going to help make everything easier
for you guys and you're like oh that'd
be cool let's take it and do and
announce our party friend
yeah 40 it's like just banging into the
wall of a corner of like some you know
gross you know frat just it's covered in
dried beer
i mean that's that's how it'll be though
i mean there will be a percentage of
people who like walk by
like i mean we're walking down the road
going to our next class so we're walking
down the road going to
a party we're in college or something
and we see a package
rolling right past us you know maybe
we're going to kick
it let's let's take it let's take hobos
for example yeah like i'm not trying to
discriminate here but
let's be honest number one former
transportation
shopping carts yeah yeah they're not
gonna stop with shopping carts
if if there's something wrong around the
street they'll just pick it up throw it
in the shopping cart
that's true yeah we'll figure a way to
open it great now we're gonna have like
a new uh like crackdown on police force
like there'll be a whole police task on
just people protecting the rights of
robots
or they're like have like a shock thing
you touch and you get shocked
that'd probably be the smartest move
like the shock doesn't turn off until
the package is deemed delivered at the
door he does like a big like you know
like those little
tags that have like the i'm not saying
there's i've ever tried this but
there's like like they're like their
little ink bomb you know
yeah it blows up oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
they'll probably have something like
that you'd have to some sort of god
knows that this thing's probably aren't
cheap
yeah i mean okay so we'll have we'll
also have autonomous vehicles
i think that like i mean so you're
you're a definite car guy
yeah so this might hurt your feelings
but i feel like eventually
what's gonna happen is like cars are
gonna be
a thing that car people have but for the
most part you're gen
generally this is way years out for sure
but i think we're gonna have like pods
that come and pick us up
yeah so it's actually it's it's a great
great
leeway into this is uh super interesting
for me
uh being a car guy for sure uh but i'll
work i work for mercedes-benz so
they're definitely at the close to the
to the top if not you know the top for a
lot of
um innovation and stuff like that um
like uh we have like a b it's called the
b class
and it was uh uh basically the motor is
a tesla motor
because they they helped tesla with like
funding and stuff yeah but in
in change for that we got some some like
the electric motor from them
and then you'll look inside of a tesla
and there's a lot of buttons and stuff
like that
that are bends oh it's kind of weird i
didn't know like you but you wouldn't
know unless you kind of like see both
the brands it's cool they collab though
yeah yeah they they want like a couple
percent stake in tesla
yeah um which is pretty common for a lot
of uh startups with
bigger conglomerates right um it's
most uh notable recently has been gm and
uh
nicola i don't know if you've heard of
nicola they're uh
they've been kind of shrouded in
controversy but
they started pretty close to when tesla
came out
and their name is nicola yeah so already
kind of a rip-off
but their whole idea was um electric
semi-trucks which is a great yeah on top
market when tesla
was like we're making electric cars and
they're like okay we're gonna make
electric crooks problem is their ceo
isn't smart
wasn't smart like elon musk he's more of
like a
amway shyster
yeah so he they never had like a real
truck and they had all this money and
then they even convinced gm to like put
in billions of dollars well now they got
bypassed
now and yeah it then like they found out
basically that
they didn't have much of anything and
their stocks just
they had the whole this stock thing they
just tanked and
uh and gm like ended up kind of like
forcing them to actually make something
so it'll be kind of interesting to see
um but yeah i think i agree
um i think honestly um well i think
mercedes is
technically uh
i think mercedes is technically uh i'm
not sure on all vehicles but
i think for some some passenger cars
they've stopped development of gasoline
engines
totally oh interesting yeah volvo's also
volvo
uh i think volkswagen have committed to
by
a certain year there's there's just no
more no more gas cars it's all
electric so is mercedes working on like
where
where is mercedes at with autonomous
vehicles like
so kind of creepy but um
they've had autonomous capabilities for
probably
eight years wow but it's just not turned
on
oh okay yeah so like i mean
and it's it's it's hard to say what
exactly like how
how good it was like there's obviously
different different parts to it but um
like uh they they started out with it's
called distronic it's like a uh
um like a hybrid cruise control like
like lane correction
yeah with lane correction that kind of
stuff and it'll slow the car down
autonomously
speed it up so basically you could set
it for 45 miles an hour
and then you would never have to touch
the brake pedal again
yeah or the gas pedal um and then
there's some that have
mild steering input or they'll drive
with around turns not super crazy turns
like i said it's pretty dumb down but
the technology has been there it just
hasn't been really turned on which is
pretty interesting
yeah i mean they're probably being smart
though i mean
like let let tesla be like the charge of
that you know like if they're they're
going they're the ones going all out
with it so like they're the ones
because i immediately think of where
when it comes to autonomous vehicles we
have
like philosophy problems like the
trolley problem i'm sure you've heard of
um essentially like if you
if you're in the autonomous car and
you're about to strike five people right
you're about to hit five people with
this car
and you could steer away at the last
minute but
when you stare away you're gonna now
kill one person so there's like this
choice of like is it better to just kill
one person than five people and then
it's like well what if that one person
is a
a kid and the rest are all old men who
are they're on their walk from the
retirement like it's
it's it's problems that humanity hasn't
figured out or come to agreeance on
and so now our technology is like super
right there so
i mean i feel like if i was a a company
that is doing very successfully in other
areas you know like
in cars i don't think that i would want
to be the first one to make the decision
to like
hit that one kid yeah well and the thing
is is like it's going to change
the whole scope of everything when it
gets here because
a lot of people don't think about
everything involved with your car
like the car may not even i think
there's gonna be a period of time
where you can still buy a car
and it'll be quote-unquote yours and
then i think at some point
um you're not gonna own a car it's gonna
be something you
uh i guess lease or rent okay
with other people or something like that
um
and i think the reason because the
reason why is i think there's there's a
lot of different reasons but
um insurance is going to be a big thing
so who at this so the the big issue is
who's who's going to take charge of the
liability now
because if technically these cars are
autonomous
it's not the owner's fault anymore yeah
it's all on the
the manufacturer so insurance companies
are gonna be
you know they need they're not going to
go out of business
i don't know where they're going to go
but they're going to they're going to
put that bill to the the
um probably the manufacturer and they'll
probably be wrapped up for a time
they'll probably wrapped up in your in
your uh
your monthly payment or whatever right i
mean yeah imagine being the ones who are
like working for
you know gm or tesla or something like
you or the legal team
has to make those decisions or like
you're the one who oh i basically am in
charge of
all the insurance for everybody who ever
gets in any of our vehicles
that's a [__] you know that's a lot
on your shoulders
i've heard of um i think tesla now has a
tesla cars you can basically your car
can go be an uber
like by itself like yeah like what when
you're not using it i don't know exactly
how it works
but yeah we already have that yeah i i
don't
and i don't know if that's because
because that
they have that that uh the capability
but i don't know it's that's still up to
like states because
there's a lot of states that don't allow
autonomous driving still um
so that's that's kind of the cool part
with that whole idea is basically like
you go to work
for eight ten hours a day your car could
be making you money
yeah it's a really cool idea basically
like you you go to work and then
um you come back and hopefully your
car's not on a ride
yeah and it comes back and then you know
you look at your phone you're like oh
[__] i made 300 bucks today on top of
great whatever you know else yeah see i
think that'd be great because i is as
long i'm sure they would have a way to
where
it's pretty like hey make sure you do
your thing during the day make sure my
car is here at six sharp though you know
what i mean
like as long as you're not getting off
work early and you like want to leave
right now you have to wait but
i think they'd probably make it to where
there's there's strict windows of make
sure my car is here so i can get to work
on time
i mean and it's an interesting idea
there are again
some again we talked about the whole
human element with these robots and dumb
asses
but again you have random people in your
car
while you're not there yeah mike it's
like you might get it back and it's
trashed
you know it's like what it just smells
like farts yeah
so you know which is already kind of
thing with uber drivers you know it's
like
there's a fee and stuff like that
obviously um
but so that's that's interesting point
you brought yeah which is interesting uh
the next part i think that will be a
little farther down the road
it's gonna be kind of weird to think
about is that we are not gonna be able
to drive
i think they're not gonna allow us to
drive it will be too dangerous for a
human to drive on the same road
as autonomous cars oh i can see that
because basically
all these autonomous cars is gonna it's
gonna change the whole landscape of
basically everything yeah there's not
going to be stop lights
they won't need them basically you're
talking to each other
they're they're uh like schools of fish
basically yeah or
or dolphins they just they talk to each
other very fast
like you might be going there you can
talk about like some of the cars not
having windows
because it will actually be traumatic
for people to look outside because
you'll be going through your
intersection and it'll be like missing
the bumper of a car by like
millimeters but it's the most efficient
way
to not because if the car stopped it's
not efficient right you want to get
there as fast as possible
or as cleanly as possible yeah but
you're in the car i mean so yeah
you get side swiped right like oh man
so that's going to be kind of
interesting to say like they'll
literally they're literally saying like
you know
it would be dangerous for a person to be
on the road
so i don't know when that's going to
happen but that would be pretty crazy i
mean yeah i could totally see that
you just shut down like a car
like autonomous cars for a few days
during the year for a classic car day
that's probably what it would be man
like what yeah
oh wow that'll be super interesting i
mean you'll be able to maybe maybe
that's the way to make money is you like
you own your own track where people come
and they get to drive
like that'll be a thing yeah it's like
like a uh like a circus show
come drive a classic car from back in
the day it's just a bunch of like hunk'd
up chunks too yeah it's just cause like
this is all that's left everything else
was scrapped wow this librarian is so
sick people
this is a cool car or even i mean so
once that starts happening think about
young kids who like start aging out of
ever having their you know driver's
license or whatever we have them
well you already see it like people kids
aren't driving as much
in general like they're like i can't
wear the stats but like
driver's licenses were down with youth
they just don't see a need to
they got uber there's other there or
they live in a city where there's a lot
of people there's just ways to get
around
i mean you got scooters and stuff you
can rent i mean yeah it's like you can
just kind of go
get around easily enough and yeah i mean
yeah we already are changing i mean
thinking about just
the the example itself of imagine
i don't know 10 years 15 years ago let's
say just for full even maybe 10 years
ago but 15 years ago
imagine telling someone like hey when
your daughter wants to go
get food she's gonna get in the car with
a stranger
and he's gonna take her there and
and that's what's gonna happen like a
complete stranger you just call him on
your phone
like a taxi driver yeah but you don't
know him
but you don't know i get okay i guess
that's not that profound then huh well
but but it's like a rant
it's like he's he's not a certified taxi
driver he's a he's just a dude he's just
a dude just your neighbor trying to make
sure
it's weird people like no i'm not let my
daughter ride in some random guy's car
yeah
yeah i know oh it's so strange we will
we are going to change though it's funny
how we're just like getting rid of the
human element more to make our
individual lives
more like just get what we want now we
want to get to where we go now we don't
want to have to have the conversation
with the uber driver we don't wanna yeah
yeah yeah it's
i don't know yeah but like i said it's
gonna be pretty crazy
yeah really crazy i'm excited for it
though i mean
it's it's weird that like we just so
happened to be in this time like all of
our science fiction movies
like when we were growing up like we're
hinting at a lot of the things that
we're actually kind of like seeing the
beginning versions of now
yeah and or even seeing like the full
versions of now really like our
technology just advances so far
yeah we're at like a super dope like
influx
of technology yeah it might destroy us
but you know well yeah
yeah yeah i know it's like everything
that's happened in like the last 10
years like if you watch the matrix again
that movie scared the [__] out of you
yeah like you're like what
i've watched it within within the last
year yeah there's so
many easter eggs in that movie the whole
movie's on easter egg oh dude you if you
really want to start i mean and then see
what your algorithms do to your brain
afterwards and with your suggested
content but you can go on youtube
and type like let's just say how
the matrix is real life enter and then
just watch like whatever
oh my god like you can and i've
definitely done this go down that rabbit
hole
i love i love like diving into like
touching yourself
i know this feels like a beard but is
this it's not
i know it's just this is ones and zeros
yeah what algorithms are these yeah no i
mean
a total mind [__] like but it really is
it's super interesting to think i mean
because those movies were
i mean they were really badass when we
first watched them but i don't think we
were
ever there was no inkling of you know
where young it was an action movie
yeah it was like the fight scenes where
they're on the freeway like fighting on
top of the buses and [__] that was so
dope yeah but now yeah watching those
it's almost uncomfortable yeah
you're like hopefully putting all the
pieces together yeah
you're like neo is jesus yeah what
yeah you're like dude if i ever wake up
and realize that i had been living my
whole life in a simulation like i'm
gonna have a psychotic break so i just
don't
i hope that doesn't happen yeah yeah uh
well but
maybe it is maybe we are living in a
simulation tim well yeah
i mean a lot of that [__] is convincing
yeah like
i i i've had i've had people message me
about it literally like
telling like they're like dude i've been
watching these videos learning
researching this stuff for three years
and
like i've come to this conclusion i'm
like i don't i mean
watching where did the egyptians go
where did the mayans go
it's like that was the end of that
simulation wipe it
pyramids are still there and then they
didn't do a full wipe yeah but then like
they got some new people
yeah plugged in some new stuff isn't it
weird how we don't even
like those all those stories or even
like you know the greek gods like any of
those things like
a lot of our history doesn't feel like
what it actually is like that was
in line with like what we are now and
how we live
in our world now like the the trickle
down of those things
are what we have now but they seem like
something other
like it's like like it seems like
another movie almost when you hear about
that those histories
yeah and it's there's a lot of
similarities still like if you like kind
of break down
obviously there's massive disparities as
far as like translations but
there's a lot of similarities as far as
like i call them like
little g's gods with little g's like
gods and stars stars nowadays are like
basically gods people look up to them
they have
billions of follow millions of followers
and people are like sick
like when they see them they're just
like oh my i touched this person
you know i can't believe leonardo
dicaprio is real that is true we
definitely
feel like famous people are influencers
with that spot in our psyches that has
always been obsessed or you know
just committed to a higher power so what
if these gods that are movie stars
are real gods from like greek times they
just never die and they just they just
fill in
a new void wow whatever's whatever's the
top of the top like okay i'll be a movie
star now
yeah hey i'm not throwing bolts of
lightning right now that was like a past
me yeah that's what i still can't right
now i still can
yeah i can they're gonna [__] unzip
their their human suit and be a reptile
oh jeez oh full circle oh god so
q anon is real let's talk about this
queue
[Laughter]
great now my [__] video is going to
be flagged on youtube
that's another thing too sensible people
yeah it's interesting but also you know
people want to believe
like the savior thing and
there's there i get it i've looked into
it and
you know it's like uh i don't know
yeah that seems pretty crazy but i can
see why people are like
whoa this is this is it it's this
algorithm is put these little
easter eggs and and jfk is still alive
and
also you're like wait what bro i mean we
want
trump is jesus yeah that isn't that like
literally what the main
i think basically he's like and i think
he's like anointed
like the save your savior he's fighting
the secret evil cabal behind doors
and i mean i so i've definitely i mean i
enjoy conspiracy theories and i also
like
i like just wondering okay like what if
or like you know
i like watching the next the next video
and like trying to really contemplate it
but then like you can't do that every
day all day because your
beliefs are actually going to start
being this kind of thing yeah it really
warps
like the way you see things and you
gotta like reel it back like all right
come on this is stupid yeah i mean i
think we just gotta like watch
our like we are human you know just like
we're just talking about we
we are the lineage of like all these
crazy civilizations before us
like as much as we want to think we're
so different we never believe those
things and like oh they believed in gods
and they had with these things like
those are there's things involved in
that that like
whether it's biological or there's like
some sort of evolution to our
consciousness
that holds on to like things from the
past we're we're clearly wanting those
and especially right now i think you
know with the badness of the world like
we're going through a massive you know
fearful meaning crisis in every way like
everybody in the world because we're all
dealing with it
and so of course we're going to like try
to find things that make us feel certain
you know it's just a human thing you
know but
i [__] but at this point i can't
confidently say
this is for sure not true because here's
what's true i don't [__] know
yeah that's the thing like i have no
idea no maybe the crazy [__] is what's
going on
that would be insane insane
uh i mean i i guess you gotta relate
back to
for me i guess i just i do believe there
is good i
do believe there is bad i mean if that's
just just
vibe off of that if it doesn't feel
right
then just don't put in the energy or
time into it that's how i feel
right because whether it's a conspiracy
theory whether it's a group of people or
whatever
you know like if if it just is like no
it's like
just change your vibe you know at the
end of the day like say it is all true
like you're saying
like what we're talking about it's like
what are you gonna do about it yeah it
sounds like you're screwed so it's just
like
after it's coming at the end of the
month anyway you know yeah pray at night
and then you know hopefully you wake up
yeah do your thing [__] enjoy your
last couple weeks of coffee you know
yeah you know um
it's crazy crazy to think about yeah i
don't know if we're ever gonna come up
with i mean we've never really had
full-on consensus consensus for like
what
is [__] going on here in reality and
like the agendas of government or any of
that stuff but
especially like the internet now we are
at the influx of
like what we call truth and what
it's all [__] messy right now it's
real messy it's it's
i mean there's there's like
like serious people normal people
um smart people regular people like
people of all kinds and all kinds of
intellect believing
very intense far out things like dude i
like i said like i'll watch these like
kind of for entertainment but i'll like
you know entertain him for a couple days
i'm like really thinking about it
but there's been times weeks weeks at a
time where i'm like
pretty convinced of some weird [__] like
maybe not reptile [__] skin suit
uh trump is jesus sort of stuff but
i don't know i guess we really we don't
know we are kind of
well it's also weird because there are
i mean it stems from like conspiracy
theorists and then there's like
certain things that have come out to be
100 true that you would literally
be run out of town for like 10 15 20
years
ago 100 and then it's like so
how it's it's not hard to understand how
people can
go there yeah it's like oh this this
thing this mk
ultra thing that came out like they
declassified that they they was they
were doing that real [__] thing so
it's like
okay so if they're doing that
is that the only thing they're doing is
yeah i mean when these things start to
become
true yeah i mean it's it's definitely
enough stuff enough conspiracy
theory has enough like uh proof to it
and like stories have been unwound like
to show us that like okay our government
along with a lot of other world
governments do
[__] up stuff and so at this point i
think that we've just
realized how long we've been lied to
let's say
that we don't like nobody really knows
what's to trust and so yeah we're
clinging to something that seems to make
sense
everybody's doing their own version of
it i know yeah
yeah it's it's it's that's that's that's
right there which is kind of everyone
has wants to like believe their own
thing
and they're holding on to it yeah might
be freaking crazy
but you know it'll be interesting to see
how it plays out i know in the meantime
i'm enjoying the bernie memes on the
internet
yeah bernie is a national treasure right
now what is like how did that [__]
happen just like a couple days ago
i just started saying burning memes
everywhere from that that photo
yeah it just looks like he's forced to
sit at a
meeting he doesn't want to be at because
let's be honest he kind of screwed him
over
and they got twice yeah they totally
steamrolled him
poor guy um whether you like him or not
you know or burn
burn you know but uh seems like a
sweetheart he just wants everyone to
have everything for free
come on yeah hey i want that too but
but uh yeah it's it's just random i mean
i didn't even notice it i didn't i
didn't watch the inauguration
no i don't watch another i don't watch
much news anyways
i know it's off topic a little bit but i
told
my buddy at work like i was like he's i
was like dude what did you think about
that
crazy stuff at the capitol and he was
like what do you mean
and i was like what you didn't you don't
know like the whole like thing
like the crazies like going to the store
in the capitol he's like what are you
talking about
dude i found that dude i felt bad like i
had
shown him porn or something for the
first time because he was like what do
you mean
and then he like he comes back next time
he's like dude me and my wife don't
watch
news he's like i can't i can't believe i
didn't know
yeah he's like it was crazy that's crazy
they did that i was like yeah
i felt bad though well isn't that the
thing that's
it's like was he in his own reality and
everything was different and then i just
brought him over into mine yeah because
and ruined his whole life his truth to
him you took away his truth
he could have been seeing things totally
differently and i totally [__] him
yeah he probably thought she was going
great he's like yeah yeah he's like yeah
smooth transition for
presidents like trump trump said
everyone's happy and yeah yeah we're all
good yeah
maybe you did you pulled him in well i
i've repeated this on here before but um
duncan trussell has has said this before
there's probably some [__]
somewhere sitting next to a beautiful
waterfall who has no idea how pissed off
he's supposed to be right now
yeah like yeah it's
actually like such a profound statement
it's true like we really do
like having instant access to like our
our
brain stem being attacked at our like
you get a notification for some [__]
that's gonna stress you out so
i know it's like i like have a news
thing on my phone
and it's got like a little slider to how
you want it really progressive you want
it really
liberal and it's like you leave it in
the middle yeah
so i just i just turned it off isn't
that crazy though like to think
because it had the same exact story yeah
but like we've now recognized our biases
and our like
our camera angles paint the whole thing
differently
you want to hear like a sort of unbiased
story okay
with the same story or you hear like the
really red version
or the really blue version it's like
it's all the same story but it divide
again we have that three-way divide
you have the crazy super right super
left and then you have a lot honestly
there's a lot of people just in the
middle that are just like
[__] you guys yeah there's so many
people that are just tired of it yeah
i feel like a majority of people are
they're either like your co-worker who
are just like
it's all so crazy that we just stopped
watching any of that [__] and if
if there's a [__] earthquake we're
gonna feel it when it happens i guess
yeah but
uh and then yeah it's the the polls are
just so
different so i mean people really
are buckling down on their beliefs oh
yeah and then like
again like if you're not if you're
again like i would be considered
probably people people like saw me
didn't know me like oh that guy's a
[__] redneck
he likes trucks and country and yeah
he's probably like got a mag of flag
outside you know it's
not true didn't vote for the guy he
didn't vote for the other guy
but that's just the the view of
everybody
it's just it's just you like this guy
you're either this that guy's a total
lib
yeah this guy's a total total you know
red redneck guy or
trump trumper dude i i said something to
uh
to a person that i was talking to just
yesterday i was messaging back and forth
um this person is is very very trump
um i literally said i typed out i'm
neither a democrat or a or when i say
i'm neither a
a republican or a democrat or something
like that or maybe i said like
republican or liberal i don't know
exactly what i said
but it's crazy how like me saying that
to this person like i literally don't
think it computed in their brain it's
like we can't you
yeah you can't not be one you're either
one or the other
it's like that's the [__] problem
guys i know it's a new black or white
complicated than that hey
hey we're trying to have a podcast here
he's gonna go crap i forgot come on bud
well tim i think we solved the world's
problems for the most part i think we
did
we're i mean i think people probably
feel way better yeah
the whole situation i think we've uh
gave everyone a very good
view into the future of driving
at least dude
i appreciate you we'll we'll wrap it up
here i i do appreciate you
[__] just letting me stumble through
like yeah we didn't really have many
subjects we wanted to just kind of bs
and i think we did that yeah that's good
that's what that's what's the good thing
about a podcast it's like you know
it's another one of those don't strangle
it things yeah you just kind of let it
evolve and be what it is
that's uh that's been one of the bigger
things is like you know i've done enough
of these now like
i mean i'm you know at least 70
and i still you know i
completely entirely 100 just like
stumble my way through it
even if i have notes even if i'm
practicing even if i know who i'm
interviewing even if i don't like it's
just i just
fall through it and people seem to
listen and
i don't know i think it's a good
reminder that like that's how we should
do stuff
yeah just just [__] do it just
stumble through it you know
just like with music just sit down and
write something and try not to
overthink and just let the emotions come
out just let it happen
so i would like i i maybe by the next
time we do one of these
in whatever world this is like you
you've got a some recordings online i
would love to
okay i would love to like have your
stuff on my phone man so i can let's do
it
on spotify my car instead i'm telling
you that's uh that's the goal that's the
goal this year is to get
a few of them up there yeah see what we
can do okay
well okay last thing uh i've been asking
everybody this lately
and we'll we'll send it off on this but
uh tim
what would you say if you had magic wand
and you're you're in charge of this
what does the world need more of right
now
um the two else light and love
i'm with it that's it okay cool
i'm [__] i'm with it is that a basic
[__] i think i have that over my
headboard in my bedroom
yeah bro i'm i'm a dude with light love
and because
i'm all about it but that's but that's
all funny that's the side i think that
that's a good one yeah dude we do need
we do
we need love and light man all right i'm
cool with it all right tim
i appreciate you all right thanks for
having me listeners take care of
yourself drink some water do some
stretches
um hug your friends next time you see
them how about that
peace out
[Music]
at what age
with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
you